《我们的生活》前情提要
Previously on This Is Us...
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
-我羊水破了  -好吧
- My water just broke. - Yep.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
-大儿子出来了  -听到了吗  生了个男孩
- First male is out. - You hear that, babe? We got a boy.
有点  不对劲
Something's... not right...
翻译:  青椒  moonshine  刁萌  小泡椒  Tracy-旋子
■
你妻子现在情况不妙  杰克
Your wife is in distress, Jack.
我找到他了  我找到他了
I found him. I found him.
我叫兰德尔·皮辛
Randall Peasing.
翻译:  献给浓子by十月  克里斯  桑葚  猪兔子  呀
我是你亲生儿子
I'm your biological son.
-托比  -凯特
- Toby. - Kate.
想成为胖友吗
So, you want to be fat friends?
翻译：小猫 冬麟 吸吸粒 时间轴: 阿包包 ccisoda
这节目太烂了
This show is so bad!
一切都是假的
Everything's fake!
我不干了
I quit.
我们失去了第三个孩子  杰克
We lost the third baby, Jack.
校对:  献给浓子by十月  克里斯
我很遗憾
I'm very sorry.
我愿意相信
I like to think that you took
你将生活带给你柠檬般的酸楚
the sourest lemon that life has to offer
后期：  宝宝  总监： 红枫Gabriel
酿成犹如柠檬汽水般的甘甜
and turned it into something resembling lemonade.
■
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
凯文
都来吃早餐了
Guys, breakfast!
快点
Let's go!
妈妈  "白家黑"让我闭嘴
Mom, Webster told me to shut up.
-闭嘴  -别这么叫他
- Shut up! - Do not call him that.
其他人都这么叫啊
Everyone else always does.
我不管其他人如何
I don't care what everybody else does.
兰德尔是你弟弟  你要给他做主
Randall is your little brother; you have to have his back.
不要  小宝贝  不行
No, sweetheart. No, no, no.
你的早餐在那儿呢  凯特
Your breakfast is over there, Kate.
乖啦
Thank you.
宝贝  我们说好的
Baby, we talked about this.
早
Morning.
早上好
Good morning.
就吃这个啊
Yuck.
杰克
Jack!
没事没事
It's fine. It's fine.
你拿水果了吗
Did you get fruit?
拿了
Yes.
要我告诉你咖啡在哪里倒吗
Do you need me to show you where the coffee is?
我知道在哪里
Oh, I know where the coffee is.
好
Okay.
-行  -给我...
- Good. - Just give me...
好
Okay.
爸爸要走了  深呼吸
Dad's off. Deep breaths.
准备...
And...
-最开始...  -是我
- First came... - Me!
-爸爸说...  -天哪
- And Dad said... - Gee!
-然后呢...  -是我
- And then came... - Me!
-妈妈说...  -妈呀
- And Mom said... - Whee!
-最后呢...  -是我
- And then came... - Me.
-我们说...  -三个了
- And we said... - That's three.
-三个小家伙  -三个小家伙
- Big Three? - Big Three!
要我告诉你我的嘴在哪里吗
Do you need me to show you where my mouth is?
不用
No.
我知道在哪
I know where it is.
行
Good.
-再见  -拜拜
- Bye. - Bye.
凯特  水果都吃掉
Kate, all the fruit, please.
你好呀
What's up?
我练了肱二头肌  肱三头肌  和左边蛋蛋
You know, I just did bi's, tri's and left testicle.
我发现那家伙有不少恶趣味
I'm really starting to get some definition on that guy.
-行了  不好笑  -好笑啊...
- Stop. Not funny. - It's fun...
-不好笑  -行了  能走了吗
- It's not funny. - Come on. Come on, can we go?
我们已经练了很久了
We've been here long enough.
-不  -凯特  来嘛  走吧
- No... - Kate. Come on, Kate... Come on.
为什么你瘦了我却没变
How are you losing weight and I'm not?
我能说实话吗
Can I be honest with you?
说啊
Yeah, please.
可能是因为我比你认真吧
I think I'm just taking this more seriously than you are.
好啦  走吧
Come on. Let's go.
世上最糟糕的地方
Worst place in the world!
亲爱的
Baby?
怎么
Yeah.
我想问你个事  可...
I want to ask you something, but...
不知该怎么说
I'm not sure how to say it.
从什么时候开始  我们要互相检讨了
Since when do we censor ourselves with each other?
不  不是...
No, I know, it's...
贝丝  我们在一起17年了
You know, Beth, we've been together for 17 years.
几乎过了半辈子
That's almost half our lives.
我懂你的表情
I know your face,
你的双手  你的心思
your hands, your soul
我对你的了解比对自己还多
better than I know my own.
你不必检讨自己
You don't have to censor yourself.
在我面前  永远不必
Ever. Not with me.
你想问什么
What was your question?
你这位吸毒的亲生父亲
How long is your crack-addict biological daddy
要在咱们六岁的女儿房里住多久
gonna be sleeping in our six-year-old daughter's bedroom?
-我去  -我就说吧
- Damn. - I know, right?
你要检讨一下自己  女人
You need to censor yourself, woman.
被我说中了吧
It's just got real.
可是兰德尔  他已经住了三天
But Randall, he's been here for three days.
女儿们现在还以为他只是你的一位
And the girls still think he's your 70-year-old co-worker
喜欢在别人家过夜的70岁老同事
who likes sleepovers.
最后我们要怎么办
What's our endgame here?
贝丝  他得了晚期胃癌
Beth, the man has Stage 4 stomach cancer.
我只想带他找医生做个初步检查
I'm just trying to get him to his first doctor's appointment,
确保他能挺过周四
make sure he's gonna make it past Thursday.
其他事到时候我们再说
Then we can take the rest from there.
好吗
Okay?
好  当然可以
Yeah. Okay.
顺便说一句  他是"曾经"吸过毒
And he's a former crack addict, by the way.
那他就住到天长地久吧
Oh, well, then he can stay forever.
瞧见没  你想都不想就这么说
See? You didn't even think about that.
最近丽贝卡很生气
So now Rebecca's all worked up
因为学校的孩子们叫他"白家黑"
because the kids at school are calling him "Webster".
你看过白人家庭
You know, the black kid
收养黑人小孩的那个剧吗
the white family adopts on that show?
我喜欢那个剧
I love that show.
我不明白  米格尔  只是...
I don't know. I don't know, Miguel, it's just...
有时候我觉得看不到原来的她了
It's hard to see the woman I married sometimes, you know?
在想什么
What?
-没什么  -没什么
- Nothing. - Nothing.
真的没什么  你...
Nothing. You...
我是你最好的朋友
I'm your, I'm your best friend.
你只是发牢骚而已
You're venting.
好朋友会倾听彼此发泄  不说三道四
Best friends let best friends vent without judgment.
就算刚过五点你已经喝了两杯酒
I'm not even gonna say anything about it being 5:03
我也不会说什么
and that being your second bourbon.
谢谢理解
I appreciate that.
问题是...
The thing is...
你老婆是个标准的好媳妇
your wife is, like, the gold standard of wives.
我知道  米格尔
I know, Miguel.
她聪明  有趣  又很漂亮
I mean, she's smart, funny, beautiful,
-性格好  身材也好...  -悠着点
- great personality, greater ass... - Easy.
她养的不是一个两个
She's raising not one, not two,
而是三个八岁大的孩子
but three eight-year-olds
可你却在这儿一杯接一杯地喝酒
while you sit here drinking not one, not two,
刚过五点第三杯就要下肚
but soon to be three bourbons by 5:05.
这些我都懂  米格尔
I know all this, Miguel.
-你懂吗  -我懂
- Yeah? - Yeah.
因为作为你最忠实的好朋友
Because as your loyal best friend,
我有责任告诉你现在是什么状况
it is my duty to remind you of what you've got there.
娶到她  你是大大的高攀了
You married way, way above your station.
建议你别让她意识到这一点
I'd be careful not to give her a reason to notice.
我老爸不是好人
Oh, my father, he wasn't a very nice man.
他跟你们的爸爸不一样
He wasn't like your father.
为什么
Why not?
你们的爸爸很优秀
Well, your father, he's good.
没有恶习
He doesn't have vices.
你们明白恶习是什么吗
You know what a vice is?
恶习是种坏习惯
A vice is like a bad habit,
比如咬指甲  但是更严重
like bitin' your nails, but worse.
-比如吸毒  -没错  差不多
- Like drugs? - Yeah, that's right.
那是我的恶习
That was my vice.
你从哪弄来毒品的呢
Where would you get drugs?
这是个好问题  苔丝
Well, that's an interesting question, Tess.
让我想想
Let's see...
我曾经吸的可卡因
Well, the cocaine I used to...
-好了  -好了  孩子们
- OK. That's good. - Okay, kids.
我们得准备上学了
Let's get ready for school, okay?
快点
Come on.
我有个好消息
Hey, so I got good news.
我给你预约了一个免疫疗法的专家
I got you an appointment with an immunotherapy specialist.
-真的没有必要  -不  这没什么
- Oh, that's not necessary. - No, it was nothing.
我公司的同事有门路
Guy at my firm had an in.
这人做了不少突破性研究
This guy is doing some really ground-breaking stuff.
谢谢  你太好了
Thank you, that's very kind.
应该的
You got it.
来吧  宝贝
Oh, hey, come on, baby.
深呼吸  好吗
I need you to take one big, deep breath for me, okay?
很好
Oh, that's good.
可以了
All right.
我的恶习是哮喘
My vice is asthma.
他的恶习是可卡因
His is cocaine.
好了  把外套带上
All right, so let's get our jackets.
去拿上你的衣服
Go and get your coat.
甜心  拿好你的午饭
Honey, here, take your lunch.
去吧
Here you go.
对不起
Hey, I'm sorry.
我知道现在跟她们说可卡因太早了
I know they're too young to talk about cocaine.
我只是
I just...
六岁吸可卡因是不是太早了
I feel like six is a hair young for cocaine...
没错  等到了七岁再让她们试试
Yeah, but seven... We let them try it at seven.
今天你去做什么  威廉
Um, so... what are you up to today, William?
没什么事  跟平时一样
Oh, nothing much. The usual.
能呆在这里我真的很开心
I've really enjoyed being here.
跟孩子们在一起  让我觉得很满足
Being around those girls-- it fills me in a way...
但我不配过得这么幸福  所以
in a way I surely don't deserve, so...
如果我待太久让你们烦了
I hope you'll let me know
希望你们要及时告诉我
when I've overstayed my welcome.
别傻了
You know, don't be silly.
有你在这里我们很开心
We're happy to have you.
那我们就不打扰你了
We'll let you get on with your day.
我想知道现在跟你们要几美元坐车
I was wondering if I could be so forward
是不是有点得寸进尺
as to ask you for a few dollars for the bus.
没事  应该的
Oh, sure. Sure.
你要去哪里
Where you going?
随便转转
Oh, you know, just around.
维克多  我的兄弟
Victor. My man.
你还好吗
How you been?
-我是赫克托  -对极了
- I've been Hector. - Right on. Yeah.
对不起  我脑子里一片浆糊
Yeah, and I'm sorry. I got a lot on my mind.
不知道你有没有听说我离开了剧组
I don't know if you heard the news. I left the show.
今天我就是来和团队开会的
Yeah. I'm gonna meet with the team today.
制订接下来的计划
You know, we're gonna strategize, talk next steps.
好多东西需要解决  好多东西要谈
Lots to figure out, lots to talk about.
太激动了
It's exciting.
对所有人来说都是激动人心的时刻
Exciting times for everyone involved.
凯文
Kevin,
你还记得当初我是在哪找到你的吗
do you remember where you were when I found you?
当然  我当时在一个即兴喜剧剧团
Yeah, sure. I was, uh, in an improv comedy troupe.
没错
That's right.
当我看到你的第一场表演
And when I saw your first show,
你知道我想的是什么吗  凯文
do you know what I thought to myself, Kevin?
-不知道  -我想的是  我做到了
- No, I-I... - I thought to myself... I've done it.
我找到了这个星球上最不搞笑的人
I have found the least funny person on the entire planet.
好吧
Okay.
但我看到了别的闪光点
But I saw something there,
所以我带走了你
so I took you on.
我给你接了广告
And I got you the commercials,
帮你接肥皂剧
got you the soaps,
我还帮你找到一份
eventually got you a job paying you
年薪三百万的工作
almost three million dollars a year,
让你名声大噪  就算你在室外27度时
making you so famous that you could wear a ski cap
戴着滑雪帽  也没人会说三道四
when it is 80 degrees outside, and no one would say a damn thing.
好了  蕾妮
Okay, Lanie...
把帽子摘了
Take off that hat.
好吧
Okay.
木已成舟了
What's done is done, right?
我们能不能就...
I mean, you know, can't we just...
别再提了
move on?
布莱恩  说话
Brian... speak.
你跟节目组签的合同还有两年才到期
You're contractually bound to the show for another two years.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  如果我不演呢
All right, and if I refuse?
好了  仔细听我说  凯文
Right, listen to me very carefully, Kevin.
电视台是你的老板
The network owns you.
他们会起诉你赔偿损失
They can sue you for damages.
他们会让你倾家荡产
They could bankrupt you.
即使有人往他们公共饮用水里
And even if someone slipped a chill pill
放了镇静药
into their collective drink,
在法律约束下  你未来两年都无法工作
you would still be legally unable to work for the next two years.
无论是在哪家工作室  电视台
That's for any studio, any network.
电视剧或是电影
Television or film.
所以...
So...
以上是好消息
that's the good news.
下面要说的这部分你不会喜欢
Now here's the part you're not gonna like.
她今晚
She's throwing this big...
要在她家举办一个大型好莱坞派对
Hollywood party at her house tonight, right?
电视台总裁和很多人会到场
The network president's gonna be there, everyone.
我要到那去  五体投地恳请他们
I'm supposed to show up, get down on my hands and knees
让我继续演《靓男保姆》
and beg to be the Manny again. Yeah.
他们是我老板  妹妹  我不知道该怎么办
They own me, Sis. I don't know what I'm gonna do.
我知道  你做的是对的
Well, I do, and you did it already.
需要我给你看那段网上的视频吗
Do you need me to show you the video on YouTube?
不了
No.
凯文  我都认识你一辈子了
Kevin, I've known you your whole life.
除了最初的两分钟
Well, except for those two minutes at the beginning.
你努力的每件事都成功了
You've succeed at everything you've ever tried.
所以接下来这样  好吗
So here's what's gonna happen. Okay?
你要去参加那派对
You're gonna go to that party,
大步走向那电视台老总
and you're gonna march up to that network guy,
然后大声说"奶爸不干了"
and you're gonna tell him, "Manny out!"
"奶爸不干了"
Manny out?
奶爸不干了  奶爸不干了
Manny out. Manny out!
你不该那样说...  好吧
Well, you're not supposed to say the... Okay.
奶爸不干了  真不错
Manny out! That's good.
问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你没出生的那两分钟里  我都在干什么
What did I ever do those first two minutes without you?
你嚎啕大哭  还拉了一堆屎
Oh, you cried, and you crapped a lot.
听起来是我的风格
Sounds about right. Yeah.
你今晚会和我一起去派对吧
So you're coming to the party, though, tonight with me, right?
-奢华的好莱坞派对  -没错  没错
- The fancy Hollywood party? - Yeah. Yeah.
-我不去  -来嘛
- No, I'm not. - Yeah.
凯文  我...  好吧
Kevin, I... Okay, f...
-我都没有合适的衣服  -凯特
- I don't even have anything to wear. - Kate.
我需要你  好吗
I need you there, okay?
一定会很棒的
It's gonna be fun.
-是吗  -绝对会很棒
- Is it? - It's gonna be a blast.
-这...  -一定会很棒的
- Is-is...?  Yes, it's gonna be a blast.
-奶爸不干了  -凯文  这...
- Manny out. - Kevin, here... here's the...
奶爸不干了
Manny out.
或是  奶爸不干了
Or maybe Manny out!
管他呢  怎样都行
Whatever... whatever works.
我们的生活
第一季  第二集
水蔓延开来
The water exhales
当微风拂动
and when the wind blows
便又是另一番景色了
the landscape is altered
这只豹一定...
this pard must be...
好了  小姑娘们  最后再看五分钟
All right, little mamas, five-minute warning
-就该去刷牙了  -可是
- till teeth brushing. - But...
没得讨价还价
It's not open for discussion.
-威廉  -威廉
- Hey, William - William!
你们好
Hi, everybody.
你这么晚才回来
You're home late.
一切还好吗
Everything okay?
没事  我很好
Yeah, yes. I'm fine.
就是忙了一天了
Just a long day.
我想先回床上休息了
I think I may just go lay myself down for the night.
晚安
Well... night.
Night.
好了  小鬼们  牙齿可不会自己变白哦
Okay, monsters, these teeth aren't gonna brush themselves.
天啊  宝贝  你刚吃什么了
Oh, God. Hey, girl, what you been eating?
冰淇淋[音近"我要尖叫"]
Ice cream.
你尖叫什么  我才要大叫呢
You scream? I'm gonna scream
我还得抱你们上楼呢
if I got to carry you up these stairs.
你们俩太沉了
You're too heavy.
我要跟大家大声宣布的事
Guess the thing I really need to say out loud
就是
to everyone is, well...
我一周内成功减掉三磅了
I'm down three pounds in one week.
朋友们  没什么  行了行了  你们不用
Oh, guys, come on. Stop. Stop. You don't...
好吧好吧  你们继续吧
Well, okay, fine, keep going.
我  我好开心  我真的
I'm-I'm so happy. I'm...
今天工作不顺  我就去温蒂家买汉堡了
Well, I had a crap day at work, so I stopped at Wendy's.
美国第三大汉堡包快餐连锁店
我在车上刚要开始吃
And I was about to eat in the car,
这个  我经常这么干
which is... all you know is my thing.
一离开汽车餐厅的那瞬间
The second I left the drive-through,
我就咬牙把那十块钱的汉堡扔出车窗外了
I threw ten dollars' worth of Wendy's out of my moving car,
然后我回到家里  只吃了沙拉
and I went home, and I had a salad.
我知道我很可笑
I know I'm ridiculous.
在你们眼里我就是个笑话
I know I'm a joke to you guys.
我知道我身材走样  或者其他叫法
I know I have body distortion issues or whatever it's called,
但这是真的
but it's real.
残酷的事实
It's brutal.
我多想让你们看看
I wish I could show you guys
我自己在镜子里的样子
what I see when I look in the mirror...
省省吧
Oh, for God's sake.
麦迪逊  你才95斤
Madison, you weigh 105 pounds.
要是你照镜子时觉得自己是个胖妹
If you feel like a fat girl when you look in the mirror,
那怎么不上秤试试呢
why don't you step a damn scale?
看到那数字"九-十-五"
And when the scale reads "One, zero, five,"
你就知道自己根本不胖了
you know that you're not fat.
还有劳丽  汉堡店的事是吧
And Laurie, that Wendy's story, okay.
不好意思  但是你只是乱扔垃圾罢了
I'm sorry, but you're just a litterer.
你就是个该死的环境破坏者
You're just a littering damn litterer.
看来是时候休息一下了
Well, that feels like a good place for a break.
你在一群胖子面前大吐为快了啊
You hulked out on a bunch of fatties.
别逗我笑  托比
You're not going to make me laugh, Toby.
怎么了  孩子
What's up, kid?
我哥硬拉我去参加个噩梦般的好莱坞派对
My brother is making me go to this nightmare Hollywood party
今晚在他经纪人家里办的
at his agent's house tonight.
我就出去买裙子
Yeah, I went to buy a dress,
结果没一件合身的  一件都没有
and nothing fit, literally nothing.
一切都糟透了
Everything looks terrible.
我一点儿都没瘦下来
I'm not losing weight.
我快饿死了
I'm starving.
说不上来
I don't know.
也许就因为这事吧
That's what's up, I guess.
好吧
Okay.
你哥的经纪人是蕾妮·舒尔茨  对吧
Hey, your brother's agent is Lanie Shultz, right?
对啊
Yeah.
凯特  蕾妮·舒尔茨
Kate, Lanie Shultz
是我所谓的娱乐圈里
is one of the most powerful agents
最有权势的经纪人之一
in what I like to call... show business.
我听说《死侍》就是她的主意
I heard that Deadpool was her idea.
要不就是《汉密尔顿》
Or maybe it was Hamilton.
我把这两个搞混了
I get those two confused.
总之  凯特你一定要带我去那个派对
Anyway, Kate, you are so taking me to that party.
不行  我不想让你看到派对上的我
No. I don't want you to see me there.
参与这种事是我最糟糕的时刻
Like, I am at my worst at those things.
凯特  伤害一个厌食症女患者
Kate, you are at your worst
才是你最糟糕的时刻
when you are eviscerating the anorexic lady,
但我依然在你身边
and I am still standing here.
我们吃过三次午餐  四次晚餐
Look, we have had three lunches and four dinner dates.
亲热过七次  爱抚过对方两次
We have made out seven times and heavy-petted twice.
我们俩马上就要
Our plane is rapidly approaching
登上爱情的巨轮了
the boyfriend-girlfriend zone,
而我呢  已经准备好上船了
and, I, for one, am preparing myself for landing.
但是我希望咱俩的话题
But I need to know that everything
不要总是围绕着体重
isn't gonna always be about our weight.
好吗  我们得在派对上尽情狂欢
All right? We need to be able to cut loose at parties.
我们要精心打扮  我们还要做爱
We need to get really dressed up, we need to have sex.
我只是随口一说
I just slipped that in there very casually
因为我认为那是
because I think that's something
我们不久后就该做的事
that we should start doing very soon.
凯特  看在老天爷的份上
So, Kate, I am asking you, please,
我请求你 咱俩能抽出一天时间
for the love of God, can we spend one fat-free night
不去想肥胖的事而是参加《死侍》
at the house of the lady who came up with the idea
或《汉密尔顿》制片人举办的派对吗
for Deadpool and/or Hamilton?
你在笑吗
Is that a... is that a smile?
没错那是代表答应的微笑
Is that...? Yes, that's a yes and a smile.
大伙  布鲁斯·班纳[绿巨人]恢复正常了
All right, hey, guys, Bruce Banner's back.
没事了  绿巨人消失了
Everything's fine. The Hulk is gone.
大家继续吧  我向大家道个歉
Let the healing continue. Sorry about that.
你舒服吗
You comfy?
睡吧  宝贝
Okay, sweetness.
晚安  妈妈爱你
Good night. I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
妈妈
Mom?
怎么了  宝贝
Yeah, babe?
我今天只吃了水果
I only ate fruit today.
你明白妈妈只是希望你健康成长吧
You know I just want you to be healthy, right?
妈妈也希望你开心
And I want you to be happy.
你开心吗
Are you happy?
大多数时候吧
For the most part.
那妈妈也就开心了
Well, then, I'm happy, too.
咱俩一起保持健康怎么样
Tell you what. How about you and I find a healthy balance together?
你觉得怎么样  不错吧
How does that sound? That sounds good?
好的
All right.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你闭嘴  "白家黑"
You shut up, Webster.
别给我起外号
Stop calling me names!
孩子们
Boys?
不能打架  不能打架
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
快住手  立刻回自己床上去
No, stop. To your beds right now.
赶紧
Now.
我应该先吼谁
Okay, who am I yelling at first?
小凯  你怎么了
Kev, bud, what is the deal?
你为什么总跟弟弟过不去
Why are you always so hard on him?
别人觉得我俩是兄弟很奇怪
Everybody thinks it's weird that we're brothers.
别人怎么想那是他们的事
You know it doesn't matter what people think.
他是你的弟弟  凯文
He is your little brother, Kevin.
你们一定要互相照应
You have to be there for one another.
你听懂了吗
Do you hear me?
懂了
Yes.
我爱你
I love you.
你能强迫他对我好点吗
Can you force him be nice?
我会尽力的
I'll see what I can do.
答应我  你要当个听话的乖孩子
Promise me you'll always be good.
我也会尽力的
I'll see what I can do, too.
我爱你
I love you.
赶紧睡觉吧  孩子们
Now get some sleep, please.
不许再打架了
No more fighting.
别让我再发现你们闹别扭
Don't make me come back in here.
晚安  我爱你们
Good night, I love you.
亲爱的
Hi, baby.
我错过哄他们睡觉了吗
Did I miss putting them down?
也就晚了一小时
Just by an hour.
我刚才...
Well, I was...
刚才在买东西
I was-- oh, shopping.
我在买东西
I was shopping.
我知道
I know...
我们最近产生了一些分歧
I know we haven't been on the same page lately.
但我们得回到正轨上来  宝贝
That we just got to get back on track, baby.
所以...
So...
把这当成一份贵重的谢罪礼吧
consider this a... way-too-expensive peace offering.
我们已经不止是偏离轨道了
I think we've been more than off track.
你觉得我们目前为止做得怎么样
Hey, how do you think we're doing so far?
当父母这方面
At parenting?
-我...  -我觉得我们也就六分
- I... - 'Cause I think we're at a six.
平心而论  从一到十
On a sliding scale, one through ten,
我觉得打六分都算很大方了
I think we're at a six and I think I'm being generous.
-小贝  -那就七分
- Bec... - Seven, fine,
但那只是因为我们有三个孩子
but only because there are three of them.
-宝贝...  -问题是
- Baby, I... - And the thing is,
我拼命想达到九分的标准
I'm trying really hard to get us to a nine.
因为这些可爱的孩子值得九分的父母
Because they are cute kids, and they deserve nine-parents.
但我觉得  只有我在努力  杰克
And, the thing is, I feel like I'm there, Jack.
只有我在以九分的标准照顾他们
I feel like I'm operating at a nine.
因为我给他们每人准备
Because I do individualized lunches
不同的午餐  挨个哄他们睡觉
and I do individualized tuck-ins for each kid
这样没人会不开心
so nobody feels gypped.
而且
And...
当你在家的时候  你就是你自己
When you're home, and you're you,
你比我强太多了
you're way better than I am.
当你做自己时你是十分  杰克
You're a ten when you're you, Jack.
但你回家越来越晚
But you're getting home later and later
当你好不容易回了家以后  你...
and when you do come home, you're...
小贝  你在说什么
Bec, what are you saying?
你不能再这样喝酒了
The drinking has to stop.
你必须克服它  宝贝
You have to reign it in, baby,
因为我决不允许我家有人酗酒
because I won't have it in my house.
-你不允许你家...  -不允许
- You won't have it in your house. - I won't.
如果这是个问题  解决它
So if it's a problem, fix it.
成熟点  解决它
Be a man, and fix it.
我不能再让你拉低我们的分数了
Because I'm done letting you lower our score.
不是吧
Damn.
-还行吧  -是啊
- Yeah? - Yeah.
太行了
Hell to the yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
你穿得挺有型的
You look dapper.
混娱乐圈嘛
Ah, show business.
太好了  到齐了
Oh, great, you're, uh--
我们该走了
We got to go, you know?
-我们要迟到了  -好
- 'Cause we're gonna be late. - Okay.
你就穿这身吗
You're wearing that?
对
Yeah.
真不错
That's great.
-你看上去棒极了  -帽子太骚了吗
- You look awesome. - Oh, is the hat too much?
帽子才是精华
The hat is everything.
是啊  那可是真正的孔雀毛
Yeah, that's a real peacock feather.
走吧  娱乐圈我来了
Come on, show business!
快去  你要是需要我就来这找我
Hey, go, okay? And I'm right here if you need me.
好吗
Okay?
-奶爸不干了  -说服他们
- Manny out. - Go get 'em.
咱们俩会惊艳全场的
You and I are crushing that dance floor.
我们走  来吧
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
快来  快点
Come on, come on, come on.
拜托
Please.
天啊
Oh, no!
来呀  跳起来
Come on! Come on.
凯特
Kate.
咱们走  得把你灌醉
All right, come on, come on, we're getting you drunk.
-来  我们喝酒去  -我们走了吧
- Come on, yup. Time to get drunk. - Let's just go.
杰克
Jack,
我是米格尔
It's Miguel.
已经很晚了  但又怕明早见不着你
It's late, so I'm leaving you a message at the office
所以就给你办公室留了条言
in case I miss you in the morning.
我之前好像越界了
Feel like I overstepped before.
你知道我爱你
Um, you know I love you,
我也爱你们一家人
you know I love you guys.
怎么说...
Hell...
或者说我只是嫉妒你们俩
I'm jealous of your relationship, if anything.
我不该在酒吧里说那些的
Uh, I shouldn't have said anything at the bar.
我好像又说过火了
Now I'm just overdoing it.
就这些  再见
Okay. Bye.
外科病理学最新进展
胃癌
你该去睡觉了  很晚了
You need to get some sleep, it's late.
你早上差不多四点就起床了
You've been up since, like, 4:00 this morning.
我知道
No, I know.
还有五分钟
Just five more minutes.
去洗澡
Shower.
然后睡觉
Sleep.
赶紧去
Now.
如果你洗得快  最后这五分钟就可以
You shower quick, you can work off that last five minutes
换种运动方式
a different way.
我很高兴咱们能聚在一起
I am so happy that we could all get together.
解决一些问题...
You know, work through, and...
凯文只是心情不太好
and... Kevin just feels awful...
蕾妮  虽然很抱歉  但这一切荒谬至极
I'm so sorry, this is whole thing, Lanie, is ridiculous.
我是说...
I mean...
曼宁先生
Mr. Manning.
我真心感激你的电视台
I'm truly grateful for everything
为我所做的一切  真的
that your network has done for me, I am.
但请允许我任性一次  先生
But please let me go with God, sir.
我之前处理问题的方式
The way I handled myself,
确实不太对  我第一个站出来承认
I mean, that was wrong, I'll be the first one to admit that.
我确实做错了
That-that was wrong.
但我们能不能抛开前嫌...
But can't we all, at this point, just, sort of, you know...
向前看  好吗
sort of move on, right?
你是个好孩子  凯文
You're a good kid, Kevin.
我很欣赏你的诚实
I appreciate your honesty.
谢谢
Thank you.
这部电视剧收视率不错
The show, it's a solid performer,
但不是我们电视台最重要的节目
but it's not the biggest thing on my network.
如果不是蕾妮向我推荐你
Without Lanie telling me,
我会从这些端餐盘的服务员里
would I have known you from one of these waiters
认识你这个无名小卒吗
passing around the chicken skewers?
-应该不会吧  -是吗
- Probably not. - Really?
我并不关心我的三流喜剧幕后
I really don't care what happens behind the scenes
发生了些什么
on my third-rated sitcom.
你知道我关心什么吗
You know what I do care about?
圣马丁  凯文
St. Maarten, Kevin.
我要在圣马丁建一个家[荷兰属地]
I'm building a home in St. Maarten
不出两年我就要退休了
and in two years I'm going to retire,
然后我会和我的爱妻搬去那里
and my favorite wife and I are going to move there.
在那之前
Until then,
我只想安稳度过这两年
I plan on just drifting through these two years
尽可能地避免痛苦和波折
as painlessly and drama-free as possible.
就像服用吗啡一样  凯文
Like I'm on morphine, Kevin,
我就想这么度过这两年
that's how I'll be drifting through those years.
好吧
Okay.
这主意很棒
That's... great, you know?
随心所欲
Go with God.
问题是...  借过一下  亲爱的
You know, the thing is-- excuse me darling.
给热门情景喜剧换个新男主
Recasting the lead on a hit sitcom,
就不是服用了吗啡  你说呢  凯文
isn't exactly drifting on morphine, now is it, Kevin?
所以很遗憾  孩子
So unfortunately, my boy,
你必须继续言这部剧
you're not gonna be leaving the show.
如果你不演  我只能毁了你的生活和事业
If you do, I'll be forced to Nagasaki your life and career.
你听说过一个叫泰勒·詹宁斯的演员吗
Hey, have you ever heard of the actor, uh, Taylor Jennings?
没听说过
I'm not familiar with the name.
我毁了他
I Nagasaki'd him.
孩子  拿着钱
So take the money, kid.
未来几年安心演戏
Ride out the next couple years, all right?
否则  我会让你成为比现在
Otherwise, I'll make you a bigger laughingstock
更大的笑柄
than you already are.
成交
Deal?
抱歉  我要去...
I'm sorry, I'm j...I'm gonna go, uh...
找我的妹妹
my sister's here.
我得去看一下她
I'm gonna go check on her.
是他的双胞胎妹妹
It's his twin sister.
一个胖姑娘
Big girl.
-你喜欢喝醉的凯特  -我喜欢喝醉的凯特
- You love drunk Kate. - I love drunk Kate.
等一下  什么
Wait, what?
进展怎么样  我喝的烂醉
How'd it go? I'm wasted.
不太好
Not good.
好  天啊  太好了
Good? Oh, my God, that's great.
不不不  不好
No, no, no, no, not good.
我不知道我该怎么做
It did not...I don't know what I'm gonna do.
-我在钓鱼  -你钓了一条大鱼
- Gone fishing. - You caught a whopper!
快收线   把我收上去
Come reel me in, got to reel me in.
这是我第一次钓鱼
It's my first time fishing.
-还会有下次  -好吧
- Won't be his last. - Well...
哪只小怪兽站在我门口
Which little monster's standing at my door?
没关系  我年纪大了  怪兽都吓不到我了
It's okay, I'm way too old to be scared of monsters.
我俩该谈谈了
I think it's time you and I had a talk.
兰德尔
我已经想上课想疯了
I can't wait until the next day of school starts.
大家快看  是"白家黑"
Hey, everyone, it's Webster!
小凯
Kev,
过来  凯文  别管"白家黑"了
come on, Kevin, ditch Webster.
我们走
Let's go.
快过来
Come on.
现在给你打电话  是不是太晚了
Hey, uh... is it too late out there?
我记得你经常熬夜
I know you're usually up late, right?
不晚  我刚刚...
No, I was just, uh...
在赶一批文件
catching up on some paperwork.
太好了
Good, uh...
我知道  发生那些事情之后
Hey, listen, I-I know I've owed you a phone call
我应该给你打个电话
since everything went down,
但因为实在太离谱了
it's been crazy out here, just... you know.
没关系
No, it's all good.
凯特都告诉我了
Kate's kept me up to speed.
很好
Good.
他们说决不会让我离开节目
They said they're not gonna let me out of the show, man.
而我...
And I...
我不知道要怎么做
I don't know what I'm gonna do, like...
他们还要牵制我两年  甚至更久
they locked me in for two more years, maybe more.
真糟
Damn.
那你打算怎么做
Well, what are you gonna do?
我倒是希望你能告诉我
I was kind of hoping you'd tell me.
因为你在乎我的想法吗
Oh, because you care what I think?
因为我在乎所有人的想法
Because I care what everyone thinks, man.
你知道的
You know that.
对你来说  我不是个好哥哥  是吗
I was not a very good brother to you, was I?
对  你不是
No, you weren't.
但你还有时间弥补
But you've still got time.
没错
Yeah, uh...
总之  时间不早了
Anyway, look, it's getting late, man, I, you know...
我该挂电话了
I probably should go.
那个...
It's, uh...
凯特在这呢  我在跟兰德尔打电话
Kate's here, it's Randall.
-好啊  兰德尔  -你好
- Oh, hey, Randall! - Hey.
总之吧  或许我应该...
Anyway, yeah, I-I should probably, uh...
回去把自己卖给电视台
I got to go back inside and sell my soul to the network,
就像妓女那样
like the whore that I am.
小凯
Hey, Kev.
深呼吸  好吗
Deep breath, okay?
来吧  兄弟  第一个...
Come on, man. First came...
是我
Me.
爸爸说...
And Dad said...
"天哪"
"Gee."
-然后是...  -是我
-And then came... - Me!
妈妈说...
And Mom said...
"妈呀"  接下来是...
"Whee!" And then came...
是我  然后他们说
Me. And they said...
"三个了"
"That's three."
-三个小家伙  -三个小家伙
- Big Three! - Big Three!
好点了吗
You good?
我很好  我很好
Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
-凯文  -怎么
- Kevin? - Yeah?
爸妈可没养过什么妓女
Mom and Dad didn't raise no whores.
除了凯特画眼线搞叛逆那段时间
Except briefly, during Kate's eyeliner phase.
是啊
Yeah.
晚安  弟弟
Night, little brother.
晚安  哥哥
Night, big brother.
亲爱的
Hon?
-给你  -谢谢
- There you go. - Thank you.
我就开门见山吧
Can I cut to the chase?
你说了算
It's your meeting.
八年前  我第一次怀孕
Eight years ago, I was, um, pregnant for the first time.
当时兰德尔在竞争公司合伙人的职位
And Randall was vying for partner at his firm.
我们毫不犹豫买了这幢房子
We'd just bought this house on faith,
虽然有好多活儿要干
even though it needed a lot of work,
虽然我们根本买不起
even though we couldn't afford it whatsoever.
后来兰德尔成了合伙人
Then Randall made partner.
房子的所有活都是他自己干的
He did all the work on the house himself,
所以我们没花一分钱
so we didn't have to spend a penny.
而且在我怀孕期间
And he made sure I didn't lift a finger
他一丁点事都没让我做
during my pregnancy.
他是个好男人
He's a good man.
不  不是好
No, he's not good.
是完美
He's perfect.
可问题是  他失眠了
Problem is, he stopped sleeping.
有一天早上  我在卫生间
And then one morning, I was in the bathroom,
他大声喊我
and he called out to me.
他懵了  你懂吗
And he was confused, you know?
他懵了  因为他...
He was confused because he...
什么都看不见了
couldn't see anything.
我的丈夫  我的靠山
My husband-- my mountain of a man--
他的眼睛什么都看不见了
could literally no longer see things through his eyes.
就好像28年来他的完美形象
It was as if 28 years of being that perfect
在那天早上彻底瓦解了
had all caught up to him that morning.
后来他...
And he, um...
他解决了那个问题
he pulled himself out of it.
他自己治好了眼睛
He self-corrected,
因为我丈夫就是这样的人
'cause that's what my man does.
兰德尔并不是没有缺点  威廉
Randall is not free of vice, William.
他的缺点就是他的善良
His vice is his goodness.
他强迫自己必须完美
It's his compulsive drive to be perfect.
所以我才爱他...
It's why I love him...
也正因为如此有时我得保护他
but it's also why I have to protect him sometimes, you know?
所以  我得问你几个问题
So now, I'm gonna have to ask you a couple questions,
问几个他问不出口的问题
questions he would probably be too polite to ask himself.
尽管问
Ask away.
你借的钱
The money you borrow.
你用来坐车了吗
You use it for the bus?
是的
Yes.
你去哪了
Where do you go?
你每天都在外面呆很久
You're gone all day, every day.
我家在费城  要坐很久的车
My place in Philadelphia, it's a long ride.
为什么
Why?
你还在吸毒吗
Are you using drugs?
-你去买毒品吗  -不是
- Are you getting drugs? - No.
你真的生病了吗
Are you really sick?
真的
Yes, I am.
贝丝  我之前就说过  而且我是真心的
Beth, I said it before, and I really meant it,
如果你们嫌我待太久了
if I'm overstaying my welcome,
我希望你们能直接告诉我
I wish you would just say it.
威廉  你待得太久...
William, you are overstaying...
贝丝
Beth.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
总得有人
Somebody has to
-把事问清楚  宝贝...  -是因为猫
- ask the questions here, baby...  - It's a cat.
我有只猫
I have a cat.
它是我的唯一了
It's all I really have.
它叫克鲁尼
His name's Clooney.
挺讽刺的名字  因为它很丑
One of those ironic names, 'cause he's a pretty ugly cat.
我来回跑是为了喂它
I go back and forth to feed him.
所以每天坐三个小时大巴
Three hours on the bus each day.
你为什么不直接跟我们说你有只猫
Why wouldn't you just tell us you had a cat?
你们小女儿有哮喘
The little one has asthma
我知道如果我说了猫的事
and I knew if I brought up the cat,
你们会让我带它来
you'd tell me to bring it,
这样就会添麻烦
that would cause problems.
但我不想给你们添麻烦
And I don't want to cause any problems,
因为添了麻烦我就得走
'cause if I cause problems, I'd have to leave.
但...
And...
但我不想走
and I don't want to leave.
六个月前  医生告诉我还有三个月时间
Six months ago, some doctor told me I had three to live.
但不知怎么的  最近我没那么难受了
But for some reason, I don't feel so bad lately.
也许是因为这个家
Maybe to do with this house.
我不知道
I don't know.
说实话  我从未想过
Truth is, I'd never thought
除了那只丑猫我竟然还会
I'd have anything to care about again
关心其他事情  所以...
besides an ugly cat, so...
我感觉自己现在很贱
Well, now I feel like a bitch.
不好笑
It's not funny.
It's not.
不好笑
It's not funny.
还有两小时我就要把胃呕出来了
I'm about two hours away from throwing up violently.
你能帮我扶着头发吗  托比
Are you gonna hold my hair for me, Toby?
不  我要待在这里
No. I-I'm still gonna be at this party,
看能不能钓到一个吉尔莫女孩
trying to bang a Gilmore Girl.
祝你成功
Well, go for both.
多一个吉尔莫  多一分快乐
Gil-more the Gil-merrier.
我的生活总是围绕着体重  托比
It's always gonna be about the weight for me, Toby.
我小时候就是这样了
It's been my story ever since I was a little girl.
每当我试着不去想
And every moment that I'm not thinking about it,
我还是会想
I'm thinking about it.
比如...
Like...
这椅子我不会坐垮吧
Will this chair hold me?
这衣服我能穿进去吗
Will this dress fit me?
如果哪天我怀孕了
And if I ever get pregnant, would...
会有人看出来吗
will anyone ever notice?
这就是我生活的重心  无法改变
It's just at the core of who I am, it's just deep inside,
八杯龙舌兰下肚也只能自欺欺人几小时
and eight tequila shots can only mask that for a couple hours.
-所以...  -我懂
- So... - I know.
其实你喝了十杯
And it was ten tequila shots,
但我懂  我理解
but I... I get it. I know.
再说一句
And just for the record,
这身衣服真的很配你
this dress is fitting you in all the right places.
这身旧衣服
This old thing?
我就随便穿的
I mean, I-I just threw it on.
你随便穿的
Oh, you just threw it on?
我想都没多想
I didn't even think about it.
他来了
There he is.
我让他们滚蛋了
I told 'em to go screw themselves.
他们怎么说
And what'd they say?
很多尖酸又刻薄的话
A lot of mean, scary things.
我要去演戏剧
I'm gonna do theater. You know?
我要搬到纽约去
I'm moving to New York.
娱乐圈啊
Show business.
你怎么在这里
What are you doing out here?
我不想睡得离你太远
I don't like sleeping far away from you.
我再也不喝酒了
No more drinking.
这不是说戒就...
You can't just stop...
我能
I can.
为了你  我能戒
For you, I can.
我会戒
I will.
我小的时候
You know, when I was a little boy,
我不知道长大后要成为什么样的人
I didn't know what I wanted to be when I grew up.
而大人们总会问孩子这种问题
Adults always ask little kids that.
我从没想出一个好答案
You know? I never had a good answer.
直到我28岁那年
Not until... not until I was 28.
直到我遇到了你
Till the day that I met you.
我才确信自己想成为什么样的人
That's when I knew exactly what I wanted to be when I grew up,
我想成为让你幸福的男人
I wanted to be the man that made you happy.
你让我很幸福
You make me happy.
不总是那样
Not always.
最近就没有
Not lately.
从今以后  我要为你对你11分用心
From here on out, I'm gonna be an 11 for you, baby.
不
No...
豁出去了
Screw that.
从现在开始  我要做12分的好丈夫
I'm gonna be a 12 for you, from here out.
11分给孩子们
I'll be an 11 for the kids,
12分给你
but you get a 12.
你能原谅我吗
Do you forgive me?
你像只拉布拉多犬一样睡在门外
You slept outside our bedroom door like a Labrador.
我当然原谅你了
Of course I forgive you.
我还能送你礼物吗
Can I still give you my gift?
你非要送我就收
If you insist.
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
-我买了月亮是因为  -我们的专属之歌
- I got a moon because of... - Our song.
对
Yeah.
我一辈子都不会摘下来
I'm never gonna take it off.
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
好看吗
Does it look good?
非常好看
It's beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
孩子还有多久会醒
How much time we have till the kids get up?
我才不管孩子呢
I don't care about the kids.
叠罗汉
Pile drive!
爸爸  不要  爸爸  别闹了
Daddy, stop! Daddy, stop!
你想睡懒觉  就得被挠痒痒
If you want to sleep in, you have to pay the tickle tax!
挠痒痒
Tickle tax.
好了   亲爱的
All right, come on, honey.
该用药...
It's time to take care of...
给
Here you go.
很好
Good.
深呼吸
Big breath.
很好
Good.
你约了人吗
You expecting somebody?
爷爷和奶奶来了
Grandma and Grandpa are here!
我先回房了
I'll be in my room.
妈
Hey, Mom.
米格尔
Hey, Miguel.